The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Forty-Seventh Episode
The Battle of Vengeance
- It's the dove!
- It has the letter from Prince Franz
that you've been waiting for so long!
You did a good job,
little dove.
It does a good job every day.
You and Franz love each other so much
that you exchange letters every day.
Tink!
I've noticed that you love each other.
Stop it!
"My dear Sapphire,
I can't wait to see you!
To me you are the moon,
the sun and the stars!"
Have a good trip, little dove!
Here he comes up! I recognize
Prince Franz's footsteps.
Every time he is to receive a
letter from his Princess...
...he is so impatient!
- Haven't you received a reply?
You must wait, Prince,
but it will arrive soon.
How about playing a little
while we wait?
Agreed.
Then I'll start!
1, 2, 3, 4 and 5!
I'll do 6!
Ah, yes, you won!
But if I were ten years younger...
Forget about your age,
please! You aren't old at all.
You're back, little one! The
Prince was waiting for you!
Why don't you read
that letter, Prince?
It's so important to me that I
don't feel like opening it right away.
He is totally captivated
by the Princess's charm.
There is a message from
the Northern fortress.
Prince Franz!
- What is it?
- Read!
What? A fleet is threatening us?!
Prince!
They have no identifying marks.
Look, they're raising a flag!
But it's the flag of Union X!
Watch out!
To Prince Franz
of the kingdom of Goldland.
Our fleet
and our army,
strong with a million soldiers,
are advancing South.
We have defeated all those who
opposed our advance.
Abandon all useless resistance
and surrender to us.
If you do not answer us tonight,
before the moon sets,
we will attack you and destroy you.
You have been warned".
Union X, damn it!
Apparently, there will be
once again another war.
This time it threatens to be
a very hard war.
I thought I would no longer have to use
the armor, but I was wrong.
Why does Union X want to attack
peaceful Goldland again?
That is the flag
of the kingdom of Carbonella.
What could they want from us?
What are you saying? The Sovereign of Carbonella
is offering us reinforcements?!
Yes, Sire! We will not leave in danger
a country bordering us.
We will fight with 50,000 men.
- 50,000 men?!
- Yes.
Now they are massed at the border.
If you allow it, they will be deployed
to defend the river banks.
Coming to our aid
is a kind act.
Make sure the Ambassadors
rest peacefully tonight.
Squadron, halt! We will stop here!
Soldiers,
I ask for your attention!
Soon the moon will set
behind the mountains,
then the Union X army
will advance from that bay from the North.
But the King of Carbonella
has committed himself...
..to check the East side
of our borders.
We must defend
our fortress.
We must defend it from all
the enemies that will attack it!
Yes!
Archers, fire!
Hurrah! Hooray!
We must reach Goldland
Castle as soon as possible!
At a gallop!
Good, the battle has begun!
Now get to work and be
careful not to be noticed.
Yes, sir!
Squadron, charge!
The enemy is entering the
castle from the East side!
Impossible, it is guarded
by Carbonella's army!
At the eastern border, there is no one!
Carbonella's army...
...has moved against us!
- It's a trap!
And I fell for it!
Little doves,
it's dangerous to stay here!
Fly away!
Go away to Silverland!
What a traitor that Ambassador is!
Anyway, I can't waste time!
What is it?
Poor pigeons..!
What happened to you?
Good heavens! Could something have happened
in the kingdom of Goldland?!
Soldier,
do you know where Prince Franz is?
He is in the Northern fortress,
knight.
Thank you.
- Carbonella's flag!
- Halt! What do you want? Who are you?
- Stay right where you are!
- Help me, Opal!
Run! Chase that wretch!
Don't let him get away! Get him!
Stop!
- But what was that?
- It felt like a gust of wind!
But these are Goldland soldiers!
Let's see if they are still alive!
Thank goodness,
this one has regained consciousness!
- Take this!
- No! What are you doing? Wait!
I thought that no one
could resist me,
except for Prince Franz.
As a soldier of the kingdom of
Carbonella, you are quite good!
I find a worthy rival in you.
What is your name?
The people of Silverland call me
"the mysterious knight."
The people of Silverland?!
But then you...
Exactly, I am on your side!
I came here to help you!
Forgive me, I am terribly sorry.
I believed that you were an enemy.
I am glad that you
realized the mistake.
Now we must try to
bring our help to Goldland.
I apologize to you once
again, mysterious knight.
I was going to the Northern
fortress, but I was attacked...
...and overwhelmed by a mob of
enemies and I lost consciousness.
I am ashamed of myself,
but now I am ready to fight.
However, I am very
worried about Prince Franz.
What do you say? Are you
also looking for Prince Franz?
I have the task of receiving
and delivering to my Prince...
...the letters that Princess Sapphire
sends him from your kingdom.
So you were taking care
of the pigeons?
Of course, it was me!
Those little creatures were wonderful!
Prince Franz!
Now the kingdom of Goldland...
...is in the hands of Union X
and in mine!
- Why do you still not surrender?
- You wretch!
King of Carbonella, here is my
answer to your treachery!
Storm the castle!
Wipe out those dogs!
Good heavens, perhaps it's too late.
Franz! Prince Franz! Where are you?
Franz, where are you? Franz!
I recognize this!
It's his hat!
- Do you know where Prince Franz is?
- No, I don't know.
Do you happen to have any news
of Prince Franz?
No, no news.
Sapphire, where could you be?
Come inside, Prince.
The evening dampness...
...is not good for your wound.
I know, but I would like to leave here.
Unfortunately, I cannot walk.
Now I don't even have
a horse anymore.
As if that weren't enough,
Goldland Castle is on fire.
I know how you feel.
But now, let me tend to your wound.
Please, moon, let Franz be alive.
Prince, write a letter
to Princess Sapphire.
What? And how do I send it to her?
I will take it to her, instead of a dove.
- But how?
- Trust me!
Perhaps she is worried about
you! Take off your cloak, please.
- My cloak?!
- Yes, your cloak!
Write on it with this piece of charcoal.
- It's the only way to write.
- It's a good idea.
Some of your soldiers might
have found refuge in Silverland.
We must inform them
that you are still alive.
I'll take care of it.
I'll be back tomorrow.
Look! Isn't that
the Prince of Goldland?
Yes, it's him. There is a big bounty
on his head.
- Let's take that bounty ourselves!
- Of course,
but we must think about
the other one first.
Let's move! Let's follow him and try
to surprise him from behind,
so it will be easier
to get rid of him.
Where the hell could he have gone?
I don't see him anymore.
Dammit!
He's so big! Help!
I'm sorry for you,
but I can't let you escape!
What the hell is happening?
- Stop him!
- Don't let him escape!
Get him!
Come on!
Stop him!
Hit him with arrows!
Kill him!
- I'll help you!
- Mysterious knight, save yourself!
- The mysterious knight?!
- I will take you with me to Silverland,
If you can keep up the gallop!
Follow me!
Curse it, they've entered
the kingdom of Silverland!
Damn them!
Take heart, we're almost
there! Hang in there!
Quickly, open the door!
It's Sapphire!
There is a wounded man!
You know, Prince Frank is alive.
- What?!
- Yes, he is hidden now.
..
.
in the Shinewood cave, and he is wounded. Then
let's go down there right away to get him. Hurry up!
Mysterious knight, please
give this to Princess Sapphire.
But... isn't this
Prince Franz's cloak?
Actually, it contains a message
intended for the Princess.
Hey, you shouldn't read a letter
addressed to someone else.
- That's true, sorry!
- Anyway, I am grateful to you
...for taking care of me.
My only regret...
- What do you regret?
- You know, mysterious knight,
I really wanted to deliver
the letter to the Princess myself.
It's my only regret!
How I wish I could meet her
before I die!
Old Dodd!
Good old Dodd!
- And who are you?
- I am Sapphire.
I thank you for all the letters
you sent me...
...via your dear doves!
Princess,
you are so beautiful and kind!
Just as I thought!
I am happy to have met you!
Now I have done my duty.
One last request, Princess:
I entrust Prince Franz to you.
Please, form an alliance
between your kingdom and Goldland!
Together you can defeat
the enemy.
Yes, old Dodd, I will
I am happy about it. I have nothing more
to worry about now.
I can finally die in peace.
Old Dodd!
Old Dodd, no!
My brave men, attack!
Dear Sapphire, Goldland is now
occupied by enemy troops.
I am wounded in the leg
and I cannot walk.
I will not be able to see you again, but I am
so happy to have met you.
I am ready
to fight strenuously.
I am always
the Prince of Goldland.
If my body remains
lifeless on the field,
my heart will be with you
forever.
I wish you to be happy
from the depths of my soul.
Prince Franz
to Princess Sapphire.
Forward!
Franz, hold on!
- Who is there?
- Hello, Prince Franz! How is it going?
- Now that I see you, it’s going better!
- Go, Franz!
Go, mysterious knight!
The enemy is annihilated!
It looks like
another group of enemies is coming!
Let's make a strategic retreat!
Of course! We will beat them!
Princess Sapphire is waiting for you
at that farm.
I'll go and inform her first.
This is yours, isn't it?
But how could he have gotten my hat?
Old Dodd, we will reconquer Goldland for you as well.
Old Dodd, I too will act according to your last wish.
Sapphire, what were
his last words?
"Goldland and Silverland should
ally and destroy the enemy."
I entrust Prince Frank to you.
I wish both of you
eternal happiness.
I will watch over you, dear friends.
Frank, he also said
that he wished...
...that you would recover
and be happy in your kingdom,
finally without any more enemies.
Thank you, Sapphire! I will try
to take care of myself as he wanted...
...and I will bring his body
to the castle of Goldland.
I will stifle the outbreaks of war
and bring peace back to Goldland.
You will help me, won't you, Sapphire?
We will join forces to defeat our
enemies and we will be so strong...
...that no one will
dare attack us anymore!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP